hey guys this morning several people
sent me messages about this problem
right here I think it was part of some
test in the UK a lot of students
struggled with this one and apparently
according to some news sites a lot of
parents couldn't figure it out either so
let's do it so this is the problem
exactly as it was given to me we have a
shape here with some of the measurements
in terms of X and it says the area of
the shape is a centimeters squared and
we want to show that a is equal to 2x
squared plus 24x plus 46. so I'm
thinking first let's cut this into two
parts now we've split it into two
rectangles there we have a rectangle is
base times height so for this one up
here it'd be 4 times X plus one and then
the area of this rectangle will also be
base times height but we don't know this
height right here this X plus 11 is the
height of the whole figure so we've got
to figure out this side length right
here so we can say this entire height X
plus 11 is going to be equal to this
question mark distance plus the four
because they're both the height of the
original figure from here we can
subtract 4 from both sides and we get x
11 minus four is seven and then these
two fours cancel leaving us with just
the question mark this question mark is
equal to X plus seven so let's change
this question mark into X plus seven and
we don't need this anymore and now we
can find the area of this rectangle it's
going to be this base times this height
now to find the area of this whole
figure we're going to take the area of
this upper rectangle and add two at the
area of this lower rectangle so now
let's clean this up we're going to do
some distribution we're going to
multiply the 4 times the X which is 4X
and then the 4 times the 1 which is four
and I'll do the same thing here we'll do
2x times x which is 2 and then x times x
is x squared and then we'll do 2x times
7. 2 times 7 is 14 and then we still
have an X then we'll do 6 times x which
is 6X and then we'll do 6 times 7 which
is 42 and now we can combine like terms
we have one x squared term so we'll just
bring that down and now we're done with
that we have three x terms 4X plus 14x
is 18x plus 6 is 24x and now we're done
with all those and then we have two
constant terms 4 plus 42 is equal to 46
and now we're done with those so this
right here is the area of our original
figure and this is what they want it is
to show and we did exactly that how
exciting